反馈建议吐槽催字幕
发送至  微博@兔牙Bobby猫
《衰女翻身》
第一季  第二集
我是普多  请留言
Hi, it's Poodle, leave a message.
普多
Oh, hey, Poodle.
又是我  米琪
Hey, it's me, Mickey, again.
记得我吧
Uh, remember me?
你把你家孩子们硬塞给我
The one you saddled with your kids,
让我照看那群熊孩子
who are awful, by the way.
我就是...  我就是觉得
Listen, I was just-- I had this thought that
你要是能抽出一点点时间
maybe if you had a couple spare minutes,
给他们打个电话吧
you could give 'em a call
让他们知道你逃出境了
and let them know that you fled the country
把他们丢给了一个陌生人
and left them with a total stranger,
你个自私的贱人婊
you stupid, selfish monsters!
总之  给我回电
Anyway, give me a call.
好
Okay.
你能行
You got this.
接到了
Touchdown!
该她了  给她一只虾
Her turn, hit her with a shrimp!
不用了  谢了
No, no, thank you.
我可不想得肝炎
I'm not trying to get hepatitis.
我想得肝炎
I want hepatitis.
这就来  小家伙
Coming your way, buddy!
这很棒吧  各位
This is awesome, right, guys?
我们为什么来穷人的地方吃饭
Why are we in a poor person's restaurant?
你哪根筋不对啊
What's the matter with you?
这不是穷人来的地方  别这么欠抽
It's not a poor person's restaurant-- don't be an ass.
这人都不是日本人  他叫佩德罗
This guy's not even Japanese. His name's Pedro.
好吧  汉密尔顿不是波多黎各
All right, well, Hamilton wasn't Puerto Rican,
但人们觉得还不错呢
but people seem to be enjoying that just fine.
好了  我带你们过来是因为
All right, listen, I brought you guys here because I,
我要跟你说个重要的消息  不是...
I got to tell you some pretty big news, and it's not...
-不想听  -不想听  你...
- Pass. - Pass? What are...?
你要戴上耳机吗  你不是吧
You gonna pop those in right now? Are you kidding me?
算了  本  奇普  听着
Fine. Forget you. Ben, Chip, listen.
-这很不容易...  -本
- This is going to be pretty hard to... - Hey, Ben,
你敢不敢舔烤板
I dare you to lick the grill.
什么  闭嘴  听我说
What? Shut up! Just listen to me.
什么味道呀
What's it taste like?
可美味了
Oh, it's delicious!
来吧  我给你一千块
Come on, I'll give you a thousand bucks.
别舔  他没有一千块
No, don't. He does not have a thousand dollars.
-傻眼了吧  -天呐  你真欠收拾
- Boom. - Oh, my God. You are a nightmare.
本  别这么做  懂了吗
Ben, don't do it, okay?
你能听我说吗
Will you just please listen?
塞布丽娜  这是要事
Sabrina, this is serious.
别碰我东西  变态
Don't touch my stuff, psycho.
我就是想告诉你们
I just thought you might like to know
你们的父母离开了  不回来了
that your parents are gone and they're not coming back.
他们死了吗
They're dead?
不  没死
No, no. Not dead.
他们活得好好的
They're definitely not dead.
但他们逃出国了
But they did flee the country.
这没道理啊  他们又没做错什么
That doesn't make any sense. They didn't do anything wrong.
这可说不好
Uh, I don't, I don't, I don't know.
这我可不敢说
I'm not going to touch that one.
我不信  你说谎
No, I don't believe you. You're lying.
我为什么要说谎呢
Why would I lie about that?
还能是什么  因为你是个说谎精呗
Um, I don't know, maybe because you're a lying bitch.
听着  我理解你们很难接受
Okay, look, I understand this is really hard stuff to hear.
这不难接受
It's not hard to hear.
其实很容易接受
It's actually really easy.
因为我根本不在乎
I, like, literally don't care at all.
好吧  但你突然提高音量
Okay, well the pitch of your voice
-感觉你很在乎啊  -我不在乎
- is making it seem like you care a lot. - I don't care!
只是觉得很丢脸而已
It's just-- it's embarrassing, that's all.
是  没错  同意  确实很丢脸
Yes, it is, it is, agreed. It's very embarrassing.
我们小点声说吧
Let's just keep our voices down, okay?
这些男士们还想好好吃饭呢
These gentlemen are trying to enjoy their dinner.
你觉得我在意这些蠢货吗
You think I care about these idiots?
抱歉
Sorry.
你怎么回事  你闹哪一出啊
What is wrong with you? You're making a scene.
懂了  很抱歉
Oh, oh. I'm so, I'm so sorry.
让我纠正一下
Let me make it right.
这样够出戏了吗
How is that for a scene?
-怎么...  -吃饭还能看戏
- What... - Dinner and a show!
赶紧吃吧  畜生们
Lap it up, you dogs!
马上给我回来
Hey, get-get back over here right now!
别命令我  你又不是我妈
Oh, don't tell us what to do! You're not our mom.
-你只是想找她救济你  -塞布丽娜
- You're just looking for a handout. - Hey, Sabrina...
发型脏乱差  衣服破到家
You with your bad hair and your Dumpster clothes!
我知道你打什么算盘
I know what you're up to,
我来告诉你
and I'll tell you something,
你不会得逞的
you're not going to get away with that.
希望你觉得很光彩
Well, I hope you're very proud of yourself.
你弟弟的味蕾全被烫坏了
Your brother has burned off all of his taste buds.
我为自己的行为道歉
I'd like to apologize for my behavior.
我明白  作为家里的新当家
I understand, as the new patriarch of this family,
你们都指望我做好榜样
you are all looking to me to set the tone,
我让大家失望了
and I fell short.
别瞎掰呼了
Stop it, okay?
没人指望你
Nobody's looking to you for anything.
不好意思  你觉得你说得算吗
Oh, I'm sorry. You think you're in charge?
我们不会听你的
We're not gonna listen to a single word you say.
你们也不用啊
Well, you're not gonna have to.
因为我很快就离开这个鬼地方了
'Cause I'm catching the last chopper out of Saigon.
你要走了吗
You're leaving?
对  艾尔巴  我要走了
Yeah, Alba, I'm leaving.
你没看外面停的那辆车吗
Have you seen that car outside?
也许是联调局的条子呢
That's a pig. Probably FBI.
我想国税局的人也快来了
And I'm pretty sure the IRS is not far behind.
等这些全被没收了  艾尔巴
And once all this is gone, Alba,
就只剩下这些熊孩子了
all that's left is this.
没钱  谁肯照顾这些小魔头
And nobody wants just this.
你要去哪里
Well, where you gonna go?
我要回罗得岛
I'm gonna go back to Rhode Island.
我在那里没有责任  自由自在
Where I have no responsibilities and nobody to answer to.
没工作的单身狗咯
So, unemployed and alone?
听起来不错
Sounds neat.
我要是能揍你就好了
I wish I could bash you.
谢谢你了  麦肯齐
Okay, thank you for your time, Mackenzie,
接下来这个家就交给我了
but I think I've got it from here.
太好了  你肯定想  奇普
Oh, wonderful. I bet you do, Chip. Great.
但为防出事  我联系了你的爷爷奶奶
But just in case, I've called your dad's parents,
他们马上就过来了
and they're on their way.
「上校」吗  太棒了  他就是个传奇啊
The Colonel? No way. That guy's a legend.
我的职业规划就是追随他的脚步
I've modeled my entire career after him.
没错  我也喜欢「上校」
O-Oh, yes. I-I like the Colonel very much.
我小时候
When I was a little girl,
他来到我在危地马拉的村子
he came to my village in Guatemala
建造了医院
and built the hospital.
他把我和我妈带回了美国
And then he brought me and my mother back to the States.
他会叫我「小蜻蜓」
He would call me his libelula---
蜻蜓
Dragonfly.
然后你就一入「豪门」深似海了吗
And you've been trapped here ever since?
你太嫩了
You're like a veal.
你该多出去转转
Got to get out more.
等下  他和提比奶奶  岁数过百了吧
Wait, aren't he and Grandma Tippy, like, 100 years old?
电话中听起来像千年老妖
They sounded about 1,000 on the phone,
所以我得赶紧离开
so I'm gonna get out of here
省得到时候还得跟他们聊一下
before I get stuck talking about soup or whatever.
行  走吧  我又不在乎
Fine, go. You think I care?
你为什么拿走我们的东西
Why are you taking our stuff?
我照看你们的酬劳呗
Call it payment for services rendered.
你住进豪宅三天  就混走一辆跑车吗
You get that for living in our mansion for three days?
我其实看好了那辆奔驰越野
Well, I was eyeing the G-wagon
但那车估计一直要加油
but I didn't want to be gassing up the whole time,
所以我就选了这辆
so I decided to go solar.
-这是电动车  -很棒吧
- It's electric. - I know, right?
等下等下  我跟你一起走
Wait, wait, wait, wait. I'm coming with you.
什么  不行
What? No, you're not.
我们不是朋友吗
W... We are friends, yes?
是啊  我们处得不错
Well, I mean, yeah. We're friendly.
但我...  我已经放了地毯了
But I... You know, I-I already got the rug and...
另外孩子们需要你
Plus, the kids need you.
-不需要  -带走吧
- No, we don't. - Take her.
米琪小姐  我砸那个男人的脑袋时
Miss Mickey, when I smashed that man over the head,
我感觉内心的「小猛兽」被唤醒了
I felt an animal in my chest wake up and roar.
我想让「小猛兽」醒得再猛烈一些
I would very much like to feel that again.
好吧  你这么说  我还怎么拒绝
Okay. I mean, how am I supposed to argue with that?
行  来跟我住几天吧
Fine, come along for a couple days,
但你得长点心眼  知道吧
but you got to keep up, all right?
我可不想一直照看你
I don't feel like babysitting.
不然就跟这群熊孩子待在一起了
Otherwise I'd stay with these animals.
但这都取决于你  小本本
but I-it's up to you, Benito.
你同意  我才会走
I will only go if I have your blessing.
好
Okay.
好吧  走吧
Okay, let's go.
这就差不多了  祝你们好运
Well, that about does it. Good luck to you.
保重吧
Uh, take care of yourselves.
如果你们有什么需要
And if you need anything at all,
就报警  千万别犹豫
do not hesitate to call 911.
坐稳了
Hold onto your nips,
这车老快了
this kitty can purr.
怎么样啊  「条纸」
What's shakin', bacon?
你说什么[原谅我]
Excuse me?
我原谅你了[失陪了]
You're excused.
能快点吗  「上校」等着我们呢
A little hustle, please. The Colonel's waiting.
-那又怎样  -拿出些尊重来
- So what? - So show some respect.
他可是战争英雄
He's a freaking war hero.
去过韩国  打过仗
Dude went buck wild on Korea.
瞧瞧这壮汉
Look at this beast.
如果这个家要找当家的男子汉
If there was ever a guy to surrender the patriarch role to,
非他莫属
it's this stud.
怎么回事
What?
你们好
Hello!
天呐
Oh, my Goodness,
你们都长大了啊
Look how big you've all gotten!
塞布丽娜
Sabrina.
亭亭玉立啊
My beautiful angel.
奇普  翩翩君子啊
And Chip, such a dashing young gentleman.
你让我想起了我丈夫
You remind me of my husband.
还有本  小可怜
Oh, and Ben, my poor baby.
我听说你出了小意外
I heard about that little accident you had.
你好  奶奶
Hello, Grandma.
路途太折腾了
Now, it has been a long day,
不如大家都上楼
so why don't we all go upstairs
换上睡衣吧
and change into our PJs?
抱歉  奶奶  我不会待在家
Yeah, sorry, Grandma, that's not gonna work for me.
我今晚要参加派对
I've got a party to go to tonight.
我很晚才能回来
And I probably won't get home until late,
你就别等我了
so, you know what, don't wait up for me.
你们...
You guys...
我知道你们这几个孩子欠缺管教
I realize you children aren't used to having rules,
但现在我要定规矩了
but all that's going to change.
现在乖乖听奶奶话  上楼换睡衣
Now, be a good girl and do as Grandma says.
不要
No.
你应该会发现我很讨厌别人顶嘴
I think you'll find I have very little tolerance for back sass, dear.
上楼
Upstairs.
当然  我告诉他只是疹子
So, of course, I'm trying to convince him it was just a rash,
但他不信
but, you know, he wasn't buying it.
我小时候
You know, when I was a little girl,
一种传染疹子肆虐了我们村子
a rash spread through our village
差点杀死了全村妇女
and nearly took all of the women.
-好极了  -嗯
- Right on. - Yeah.
我们俩都有疹子的故事可聊了
Very cool that we both have rash stories.
这就是我家啦
So, this is it. Home, sweet home.
对  我家离机场很近
Oh, yeah, I live real close to the airport.
特别方便  你渴了吗
Super convenient. Thirsty?
嗯
Yeah.
干杯
Cheers.
来吧  干杯
There we go. Cheers.
杰米
Jimmy?!
我滴娘咧  你还活着
Holy crap, you're alive.
你看起来不错
Oh, you look good.
-什么  别碰我  -你看起来真好
- What? No. Get-Get off of me! - You look really good.
-你干什么  -我很高兴见到你
- What are you doing? - Oh, I'm happy to see you.
我是杰米
I'm Jimmy.
-我是她男友  -他不是我男友
- I'm the boyfriend. - He's not my boyfriend.
我们已经在一起睡了十年了...
Oh, come on. We've been plowing for, like, ten years...
你怎么在我家  杰米
What are you doing here, Jimmy?
你住在我家吗
Are you living in my place?
不  就是管道...
No. The... the pipe is just, like...
-管道吗  -是...
- Oh, the pipe? - Yeah, and it...
滴水了
there's a, there's a... you got a drippy...
管道漏水吗
I got a drippy?
我想念这里的味道
I missed the smells.
我要赶你走
Okay, well, you can smell my ass
你闻个屁吧  赶紧走
when you kiss it good-bye. Leave.
我感觉你对我有点敌意
Okay, you know what, I'm sensing some major hostility here,
我不计较  但这是因为撞车那事吗
which is fine, but is it about the car thing?
你是说你开车撞了我吗
The car thing where you ran me over?
-是  -没错
- Yeah. - Yes, it is.
但我跟你道歉了
Okay. Well, I said I was sorry.
没  你没道歉
No, you didn't say you were sorry.
我现在道歉
I'm saying it now.
杰米  你都没停下看我受没受伤
Jimmy, you didn't even stop.
我以为你死了
I thought you were dead!
你停下了吗
Did you stop?
你停下  想过我的感受了吗
Did you stop and think about how it made me feel?
滚出去
Get out!
-我说真的  滚  -走就走
- I'm serious. Get out. - Oh, fine!
我也不需要
Well, guess what. I don't need this,
我不需要你  也不需要这条浴衣
and I don't need you and I don't need this robe.
拿走浴衣吧  我可不要这浴衣
Come on. Keep the robe. I don't want the robe.
不  我不想要
No, I don't want it.
这会让我想起你  我不想这样
It makes me think of you, and I hate it.
等一下
Wha... Hold on.
你纹了新纹身吗
Did you get a new tattoo?
没错
Yeah, I did.
我后悔了
I regret it.
我提点你一下
And a word to the wise:
那个印度赌场的高利贷
that loan shark from the Indian casino,
他一直在附近打听你  等他来...
he's been poking around, so when he comes to get...
他让我想起了我表哥  维克多
He reminds me of my cousin, Victor.
他母亲怀了他14个月
In the womb for 14 months.
大头症  真惨
Big head. Very sad.
别在意他  他根本不重要
Yeah. Don't pay attention to him. He's no one.
你想出去
Hey, you want to get out of here,
感受一下镇上的风采吗
go crank the lights up on this town?
我不知道你说什么
I don't know what you say.
没关系  吃掉这个
That's okay. Uh, just take this,
我稍后再跟你解释
and I will explain the rest later.
不  不用了
No. No, thank you.
别担心  药性很弱
Oh, don't worry-- it's super mild.
不用了  我胃口不好  吃不了这个
Oh, no, no, I-I can't, 'cause I have a sensitive stomach.
-我也是  吃一半吧  -不  这东西不好
- Me, too. Just take half. - No, it's-it's no good.
就放在舌头上  告诉我味道如何
Just put it on your tongue and tell me what it tastes like.
我不能吃  这东西不好
I can't do it! It's not good.
艾尔巴  朋友之间应互相信任
Alba, friends trust each other.
不行  我说了不吃
Plea... I said no!
如果你不吃  我就解雇你
I'll fire you if you don't.
我开玩笑呢
I'm just kidding!
抱歉  瞧我把你吓的
Oh, I'm so sorry. Your face. I scared you.
我不能解雇你  你都不是我家佣人
I can't fire you-- you're not even mine.
-你不用吃  -谢谢你
- You don't have to take it. - Oh, thank you.
因为你已经吃了
'Cause you already took it.
等下  什么
Wait, what?
我之前在酒里放了一片
I popped one in your beer earlier.
你开玩笑吧  肯定是玩笑吧
No, y-you're joking. This is a joke, right?
我当然是开玩笑了
Of course I'm joking!
谁会那么做啊
Who would do that?
-我看不出来你是不是开玩笑  -我知道
- I can't tell, I can't tell. - I know.
其实我开玩笑说是开玩笑
Actually, I'm joking about joking.
你已经吃下有十分钟了
I'd say you have about ten minutes.
什么  不不不
Wha...? Oh. Oh, no, no.
我要去梳洗打扮一下了
Yeah. You know what, I'm gonna go freshen up.
-这会很有意思的  -别走啊
- This is gonna be fun. - Don't leave. No.
你干什么
What are you doing?
我要去做个烤奶酪
I was gonna go make a grilled cheese.
-你干什么  -我要出去
- What are you doing? - I'm going out.
如果奶奶醒了怎么办
What if Grandma wakes up?
那你就告诉她...
Well, you can tell her to eat a big fat...
你们俩要去哪儿呢
And where might you two be going?
我就是想去做个烤奶酪
I was just going to make a grilled cheese.
不  是我想去做烤奶酪
No, I-I was gonna go make a grilled cheese.
真巧啊
What a coincidence--
大家晚上都想吃烤奶酪
everyone's got a midnight hankering for some grilled cheese.
好吧  我要出去  我朋友富士今晚打碟
Okay, fine, I'm going out. My friend Fuji is deejaying.
真有趣  你听到了吗  「上校」
Oh, how fun. Did you hear that, Colonel?
富士今晚打碟
Fuji is deejaying.
不是什么大事  我就是过去跳个舞
Look, it's not that big of a deal-- I'm just going dancing.
怎么不早说  你可以在这里跳啊
Well, why didn't you say so? You can dance right here.
什么
What?
你听到了  跳吧
You heard me. Dance.
-别这样  奶奶  这太扯了  -赶紧跳
- Come on, Grandma, this is insane. - Dance!
你们两位绅士不能让女生独舞吧
You gentlemen aren't going to let a lady dance alone, are you?
来吧
Go on.
跟她一起跳
Join her.
这样好多了
That's better.
这样才好玩嘛
Now we're having fun.
你感觉怎么样啊
How you doing over there?
-我还好吧  -是吗
- I... Good, I think. - Yeah?
我迈不动腿  但...
My legs are heavy, but...
精神上似神仙
my mind is light.
而我的背部汗流成河
And my back is slick with a river of sweat.
我感觉很放松
I feel relaxed but...
但精神又很集中
also focused.
有点暖和
Kind of warm, too.
总体上很好  我感觉很棒啊
Overall, good. I feel good!
这就好  你说了很多啊
Great. That was a lot of info there.
-谢谢了  -嗯
- Thank you so much. - Yeah.
这酒就别一饮而尽了
That's not what you want to gulp.
别一饮而尽
No... no guzzling.
好吧  你自己要喝的
All right, that's on you.
你想跳舞吗
Do you want to go dance?
来吧  老娘要出场了
Yeah, lead the way, bitch!
我们要死了
We're gonna die!
-什么  -好了  好了  到家了
- What? What? - Okay, okay, we're home.
我们到家了  好极了
We're home. Right on.
我头好疼啊
Oh, my mind is in pain.
艾尔巴  天呐  你那么大声干什么
Oh, Alba, God, do you have to scream?
震得我头都炸了
It's like nails in a blender.
我们回家  睡一觉吧
Let's just get inside and pass out, and then...
我家窗户怎么开着
Wait, why is my window open?
杰米是不是提过那个高利贷的事
Didn't Jimmy mention something about a loan shark?
等一下  我打个电话
Hold on a second. I got to make a phone call.
-你说的话  都听不懂  -别出声...
- Oh, the words you say mean n-nothing. - Just shu...
被你打败了
You're killing me.
杰米
Oh, hey, Jimmy, hey.
我家靓哥怎么样啊
How's my big, sexy side of beef, huh?
你干什么呢
What are you doing?
上大号呢
Just dumping out.
我早上吃了些隔夜的蛤蜊...
I ate some leftover clams for breakfast--
结果就开始闹肚子了
they're wreaking havoc on my insides.
你怎么样啊
What's up with you?
没什么啊
Nothing.
我就是想让你过来
I just was hoping that you could come over here
「闹一下」我的肚子呀
and... wreak havoc on my insides.
你很想要吧
You do, do you?
欲火焚身呢
Yeah. Big-time.
快过来  征服我吧
Get over here. Take me.
你自找的啊
You asked for it.
-我拉得到处都是  清理完就过...  -真是够了
- I'm gonna mop up, and I'll be right ov... - I mean...
奶奶说要下来吃早...
Grandma says come down for break...
你干什么
What are you doing?
我要让这个女人尝尝我的厉害
This woman needs to know who she's messing with.
-你确定这样做好吗  -这就像过招
- You sure that's a good idea? - Oh, it's all part of the dance.
她出过招了  现在换我了
She came at me, now I'll come at her,
两人交手  斗智斗勇  其乐无穷
and round and round we'll go in this cruel little game of wits.
-听起来你不正常  -是吗
- You sound insane. - Do I?!
我从米琪那里学来的
I learned it from Mickey.
至少她肯跟我公平过招
At least she appreciated a healthy rivalry.
走吧
Come on.
那是「上校」的培根
That's the Colonel's bacon!
你想吃  就好好表现
You can have bacon when you earn bacon.
你们这群孩子真是被宠坏了
You children have been spoiled rotten.
说真的
I mean, for Goodness' sake,
你们之中就本有点家教
Ben is the only one of you with any manners.
当然这不能全怪你们
Now, I suppose it's not entirely your fault.
这都怪我那蠢儿子和你们那个风骚的妈
I blame my idiot son and that whore mother of yours.
但我要重振家风
But I will restore dignity to our family
直到死为止
if it's the last thing I do.
奇普  从现在开始
Chip, from now on,
你就是「上校」的学徒了
you'll be the Colonel's apprentice.
先从将食物切成小块喂他吃开始吧
You can start by cutting his food into little pieces and feeding him.
没有看护喂他吗
Doesn't he have a nurse for that?
有啊  就是你
He does. You.
而你这个「小公举」
And, uh, little Miss Rosemary Kennedy here
就要学习做个淑女
will learn to behave like a lady,
不然就吃不了兜着走
or she will suffer the consequences.
遵命  奶奶  都听你的
Yes, Grandma. Whatever you say.
很好
Good.
如果没什么事了
Now, if you don't mind,
我要好好享用咖啡了
I'd like to enjoy my coffee.
干什么啊
What? What?
这下衣服不能穿了  你个老妖婆
You ruined my blouse, you wrinkly bitch!
你穿不了是因你长胖了
Your blouse was ruined by your inability to fill it out.
赶紧去再煮一壶
Now, go put on a fresh pot.
我们来吧
Let's do this.
我到了
Oh, yeah, here we go.
太棒了
Oh, yeah.
等下  等下
Wait, wait.
我的天呐
My Goodness.
米琪
Mickey?
米琪  -该走了
Mickey. - Time to boogie.
快走啊
Do something!
别担心  我搞得定
Don't worry, I got this.
吸姐的尾气吧  混蛋
Suck solar, bitch.
怎么回事
What-What's happening?
不不不不
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
四千二  米琪
$4,200, Mick.
钱在哪儿
Where is it?
你觉得在哪儿呢
Where do you think it is?
你觉得我像是闹着玩吗
Do I look like I'm playing games?
好吧  我没钱
Okay. I don't have it.
不如你把那辆车拿走
But what do you say you take that car out front
我们就两清了
and we call it even, huh?
我可不要你偷来的车
I don't want your stolen car.
我不是高利贷  不是偷车贼
I'm a loan shark, not a car thief.
你俩都给我坐下
Sit. Both of you.
米琪  我很害怕  你生活太悲惨了
Mickey, I am scared. Your life is very sad.
我知道  人艰不拆好不好
Yes, I know that, okay? Thank you.
我想回格林威治的家
I want to go home to Greenwich.
太晚了  我们都立完牌坊了
It's too late. We've burned that bridge.
你自己立完了
You burned that bridge.
我们俩都立了
We both burned that bridge.
谁先开始的并不重要
It doesn't matter who lit the match.
我们必须求他们原谅
We must beg their forgiveness.
奇普少爷会给你钱还债的
Mr. Chip will give you the money to pay for this mess.
我才不要跟一个12岁的小屁孩借钱
I am not borrowing money from a 12-year-old.
说实话  米琪
Honestly, Mickey,
我真替你悲哀啊
I'm depressed for you.
你真是穷得叮当响啊
You literally have nothing.
我都跟你说了
Yeah, that's what I said.
我也不想这么做  但你逼我的
Well, I hate to do it, but you leave me no choice.
把你的手放在桌上吧
Put your hand flat on the table.
好吧  我知道你得走个过场吓唬我
Okay, look, I know you got to do the whole tough guy routine,
但我们都知道
but, listen, you and I, we all know
你绝不会对一个女人下手
that you're not actually gonna hit a lady.
天呐
Oh, my God!
你打碎手骨了
You crushed me!
另外一只手  快点  还得去接我儿子
Next hand. Hurry. I got to pick my boy up from day care.
不不不  我有钱  我有钱
No, no, no, no, no! I got the money, I got the money.
-在哪儿  -康涅狄格州  给我几个小时
- Where? - It's in Connecticut. Just give me a couple hours.
你觉得我傻吗
You think I'm an idiot?
-伸手  -不要不要不要
- Give me that hand! - No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no!
-我先把艾尔巴押给你  -什么
- I'll leave you Alba as collateral. - What?!
-快点  -好好好
- Hurry. - Yeah, yeah, yeah.
什么  别丢下我
What? Please don't leave me.
艾尔巴  听我说  你得信我啊
Alba, listen to me. You got to trust me right now, okay?
求你相信我吧
Please trust me.
我不相信你  你给我下药了
No, I don't trust you. You drugged me.
我也是为了你好啊
Well, that was for your own good.
瞧瞧你解放了多少啊
I mean, look how far you've come.
好了  听着  你得帮我这个忙
All right, listen, I need you to do me a favor.
我帮过你  现在换你帮我了
I did you a favor. It's your turn to do me a favor.
好闺蜜就该两肋插刀
That's what best friends do.
我们是好闺蜜吗
We are best friends?
不知道啊  你说呢
Well, I don't know. Are we?
-是  -好了
- Yeah... - All right.
「瞧瞧啊  瞧瞧我
"Meh, meh, meh. Look at me.
我是「上校」  我是战争英雄」
I'm the Colonel. I'm a war hero."
我让你看看什么是战争  你个老东西
I'll show you a war, you old bastard.
你怎么会变成这样啊
What happened to you?!
我以前那么爱你  爷爷
I loved you, Grandpa!
那么爱你
I loved you!
你干什么呢
What are you doing?
没什么  就是冥想呢
Nothing. Just, uh, meditating.
你的脸怎么成这样了
What happened to your face?
那个老妖婆把我的化妆品扔掉了
Oatmeal Boobs threw away my makeup.
你素颜长这样吗
Do you always look like that?
闭嘴吧  我一夜没睡  一直跳舞呢
Shut up. I was up all night dancing the Charleston.
那个老太婆太可怕了
The woman is awful.
谁说不是呢  「上校」毁了我的生活
Tell me about it. The Colonel's ruining my life.
你说什么呢  他已经是个植物人了
What are you talking about? The guy's a vegetable.
他就是心机老头子
He is a manipulative scumbag,
必须要阻止他
and he needs to be stopped.
听我说完  好吗  因为我知道...
Just hear me out, okay? 'Cause I know that...
谢天谢地你来了  你救救我们吧
Oh, thank God you're here. You got to help us.
你把我们丢给了一个虐待狂
You left us alone with an abusive lunatic.
你脸怎么成这样了
What happened to your face?
-吓人吧  -是啊
- Spooky, right? - Yeah.
你到底要不要帮我们了
Are you gonna help us or not?
各位  我和艾尔巴俩人过得不错...
Guys, Alba and I got a pretty sweet thing going on, so...
开个价吧
Name your price.
你毕竟是家人
Well, you are family.
我得看在家人的情分上打个折
So I guess I'll have to take that into consideration.
就给我四千二吧
I'll come down to $4,200.
怎么这么精确  但好吧
Bizarrely specific but fine.
好  把他们弄出去
Okay, just get them out of here,
因为如果
'cause if I have to scrub
让我再给「上校」擦洗一次恶心的纹身身子
the Colonel's disgusting tattooed carcass one more time,
我就会疯掉的
I'm gonna lose my mind.
这家伙还有纹身呢  真不错啊
Guy's got tattoos, huh? That's pretty sweet.
有十字架  蜻蜓
He's got a cross, a dragonfly,
-还有吟诵大海的诗词...  -慢着
- some weird poem about the sea... - Hold on a second.
你有蜻蜓的纹身吗
He has a dragonfly tattoo?
是啊  很大  就在下垂的胸下
Yeah. It's big. It's right on his wrinkly tit.
-在这里  -没错
- Right here? - Yeah.
要搞出大新闻了
Oh, my God.
提比  抱歉就这么闯进来了
Tippy. Hey, super sorry for the barge-in.
-我是米琪  我们通过电...  -我知道你是谁
- I'm Mickey. We spoke... - I know who you are.
你那个风骚姐姐抢走了我儿子
You're the sister of that whore who stole my son.
没错  我是她妹  听着
Yeah. That's me. So, listen,
我跟你说要让你照看孩子们
I know I told you I needed you to watch the kids,
但我这边觉得有义务照顾他们
but a couple things fell through on my end,
所以就不用你再照看了
so we won't be needing you anymore.
很抱歉麻烦你跑来了
Sorry for the inconvenience.
你离开的时候  可以挑辆车走
Hey, you know what? Grab a car on your way out.
我不打算走
Oh, I'm not going anywhere.
那真太可惜了
Well, that's unfortunate.
你这是逼我揭开一见丑闻
You leave me no choice but to reveal a scandal
不可外扬的家丑
so very scandalous
那会毁了佩莫顿一家的名誉
that it will shatter the foundation of the Pemberton name.
没错  「上校」
That's right, Colonel.
你是采花丛中的小蜜蜂啊
You've been a busy boy, haven't you?
到处拈花惹草
A very bad, busy little boy.
我们都知道「上校」热情似火
Now, we all know the Colonel is a man of many passions.
但女人最能激起他心中的火焰了
But none burn brighter than that of the female flesh.
即便是他  也经不住
Even he was no match for the temptresses
危地马拉岛国妖妇的诱惑
who inhabit the tiny island nation of Guatemala!
-危地马拉不是个岛  -你能不...
- Guatemala isn't an island. - Would you... I...
-我在解决问题呢  -我懂  就是拖得太长了
- I'm doing a thing. - I know. It's just taking forever.
-我马上就说到重点了  -快点说啊
- I'm building up to something. - Build faster.
你能不打断我吗
Could you stop interrupting me?
-你就稍微...  -谢谢  总之...
- If you just do it... - Yeah, okay! Thank you! Okay. Anyway...
毋庸置疑
there's no denying
「上校」为危地马拉国
that the Colonel has done a great many things
做了不少贡献
for the landlocked nation of Guatemala.
他会名垂青史  因为他建造了马路
His legacy will forever be etched in the roads he's paved,
建造学校
the schools he's built,
还留下了他的私生女
and the faces of his bastard children.
没错
That's right.
「上校」是艾尔巴的父亲
The Colonel is Alba's father!
不然他怎么会把蜻蜓纹在心间呢
Why else would he have a dragonfly tattoo over his heart,
绝逼是为了纪念他的「小蜻蜓」
if not to honor his precious libelula?
怎么了  「上校」
What's the matter, Colonel?
说不出话了吗
Cat got your tongue?
我想你说的纹身
I believe the, uh, tattoo you're referring to
是B4轰炸机
is the B-24 Bomber.
跟他开过太平洋的那架飞机很像
Much like the one he bravely flew over the Pacific.
好吧  好吧
Yeah. Okay. Well, um...
谢谢您为国效力
Thank you for your service.
你跟你姐真是一个德行
You're no different from your sister.
就是一个拜金女
You're just a dimwitted gold digger
赖上佩莫顿这颗摇钱树了
trying to suckle from the mighty Pemberton teat.
只要我还有一口气
Well, so long as I have breath in my body,
你就永远...
you will never...
-她不会有事吧  -没事  当然了
- Is she gonna be okay? - Yeah, yeah. Of course.
但她摔坏了两边髋关节
Well, she did break both of her hips, you know?
所以不可能没事
So, no, she's not.
有人今晚照看这些孩子吗
These kids have somebody to watch them tonight?
有吧  我能留下来
I mean, yeah, I guess I could stay,
如果你们需要我
you know, if you guys need me.
-好啊  如果你不太忙  -我很忙
- Yeah, if you are not busy. -I am busy.
我非常忙  奇普
I'm very busy, Chip.
这不是问题  问题是...
That's not the question. The question is...
你想让我留下吗
you know, do you want me to saty?
你们死命留我  我就留下
I can, if you are desperate.
倒也不是「死命」留你  但...
I mean, I wouldn't say the word "desperate", but...
没错  严格来说  我们需要有人看护
Yeah, I guess, technically, we need somebody.
-所以是严格来说  好吧  -对
- So it's technically. Alright.  -Yeah.
瞧瞧啊
Look at that.
感觉我们都需要彼此啊
Sounds like we all need each other.
这人谁啊
Who is he?
我叫杰米  我是她男友
I'm Jimmy. I'm the boyfriend.
他不是我男友
He's not my boyfriend.
我们已经在一起睡了十年了
We've been plowing for like teen years.
杰米  别说了  这时候就别跟我争了
Jamie, come on. Let's not do this right now. OK?
拿下来吧  哈喇流得到处都是
Come here, Ben. Let's get you out of this thing,
别又害别人受伤了
before somebody gets hurt.
你个小坏蛋
You little murderer.
艾尔巴呢
Where is Alba?
字幕组
ZiMuZu.tv
原创翻译  双语字幕
最快首发美剧日剧下载请登录
字幕组网站www.ZiMuZu.tv
翻译:  兔牙Bobby猫
校对:  兔牙Bobby猫
时间轴:  壬虚浪影
后期:  鱼骨头
总监： 兔牙Bobby猫